喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
喜欢
Yes.
《飓风营救》
- Mr。Mills，how are you？- I'm fine.
- 米尔斯先生 你好吗？ - 很好
- How are you？- Fine.
- 你呢？ - 很好
- I suppose you wanna see it again？- Lf you don't mind.
- 我猜你还想再看一遍？ - 你不介意的话
- You know where it is。- Oh，yeah.
- 你知道放在哪里 - 哦 是的
If I charged you a dollar every time you came to examine the machine…
如果你每次来看机子我都收你一元…
…you'd probably own it。It's the one all the pros use.
…都够你买一台了 内行都用这个
Mariah Carey。Beyonce。Gwen Stefani.
玛丽亚·凯莉 碧昂丝 格温·史蒂芬尼
Really？Who's Beyonce？
真的？碧昂丝是谁？
Just kidding。I'll take it.
开玩笑呢 我要了
Excuse me，sir。The adult party's in the front.
等等 先生 家长聚会在前面
- I'm Kim's father。- Excuse me，I work for her father.
- 我是金姆的父亲 - 不好意思 我就是为她父亲工作的
- Her real father。- It's okay，Cyril。I got it.
- 我是她的亲生父亲 - 没事 西里尔 我来
- Hello，Bryan。- Lenore.
- 你好 布莱恩 - 丽诺尔
I just wanted to give Kim her present.
我只是来给金姆礼物的
We're letting the kids have their space.
有专门给孩子们放礼物的地方
- Put it with the others。- I wanna give it to her myself.
- 就跟其他人的放一起吧 - 我想亲手交给她
- Still having trouble following the rules。- Oh，come on，Lennie.
- 仍是我行我素啊 - 哦 拜托 莉妮
- I've asked you not to call me that。- Excuse me。Lenore.
- 叫你不要这么叫了 - 抱歉 丽诺尔
- Dad！- Oh，my darling.
- 爸爸！ - 哦 亲爱的
- Hi。- Hello，my sweet.
- 嗨 - 你好 我的宝贝
- Happy birthday。- I was telling your father…
- 生日快乐 - 我在跟你爸爸说…
- …how we arranged the presents。- Here.
- …我们如何放置礼物的 - 给你
It's bad manners to open the one…
拆了这个礼物 而不拆其他的…
- …and not the others。- Go on。Open it.
- …可不是个好习惯 - 来 打开它
- Cool。- A karaoke machine？
- 好酷哦 - 卡拉OK机？
- Well，I figured she wants to be a singer。- When she was 12，Bryan.
- 我记得她想成为一个歌星 - 那是12岁的事了 布莱恩
- We've moved on。- Thank you，Daddy.
- 我们都变了 - 谢谢 爸爸
My pleasure.
你喜欢就好
- I still wanna be a singer。Don't tell Mom。- You got it.
- 我还是想当歌手 不要告诉妈妈 - 好的
Here。One for the book.
给 照张相作个纪念
- We have a professional photographer。- Big smile，sweetie.
- 我们有职业摄影师 - 笑一笑 宝贝
That's my girl.
真是我的乖女儿
Oh，my God。Oh，my God！
哦 天哪 哦 天哪！
Oh，my God！Oh，my God！Oh，my God！
哦 天哪！哦 天哪！哦 天哪！
Oh，my… Stuart！
哦 天…斯图尔特！
Stuart，I love you！I love you！I love you！
斯图尔特 我爱你！我爱你！我爱你！
Happy birthday，sweetie.
生日快乐 宝贝
- Oh，Stuart，you're impossible。- I know.
- 哦 斯图尔特 太意外了 - 我知道
- Hey，Bryan。- Stuart.
- 嗨 布莱恩 - 斯图尔特
- She's not a little girl anymore，huh？- I guess not.
- 她不再是个小女孩了 是吧？ - 我想是的
- Will you join us for lunch？- No，thanks.
- 留下来吃午饭吧？ - 不了 谢谢
I just wanted to be here to wish her a happy birthday.
我只是来这祝她生日快乐的
- Good to see you，Bryan。- You too.
- 很高兴见到你 布莱恩 - 我也是
Thanks.
谢谢
（生日快乐 金姆）
（金姆 17岁）
（金姆 16岁）
- Hey。- Hey.
- 嗨 - 嗨
You forgot.
你忘了
Come on in.
进来
It's not like I didn't call to remind you。Third Saturday in May？
我都打电话提醒你了 五月的第三个星期六 对吧？
- Red meat，red wine？Sound familiar？- He probably had a lot on his mind.
- 牛排 红酒？很熟悉吧？ - 也许他脑子里塞了太多事了
Yeah，the busy life of a retiree。Every day a new adventure.
是啊 退休工人的忙碌生活 每天都是个新冒险
What does a retiree do，anyway？Take naps？Play golf？
不过退休了都做些什么？ 睡睡觉？打打高尔夫？
- Hit on rich widows？- That takes care of the morning.
- 搭讪富孀？ - 一上午有的忙了
Yeah，well，come on，guys。You know why I'm here.
得了 伙计们 你们知道我在这的原因
Yeah，how's that going？
是啊 怎么了？
Okay。We had her birthday today.
没什么 我们今天给她庆生
Can you believe my Kimmy's 17？
你们相信我的金姆都17岁了吗？
Seventeen？
17岁？
- To Kim。- Lennie still got a hard-on for you？
- 为了金姆 - 莉妮还恨你吗？
She's not Lennie anymore。She's Lenore.
她不再是莉妮了 她叫丽诺尔
Oh，she's still got a hard-on.
哦 她还恨你呢
- And the husband？- The same。Perfect.
- 她丈夫呢？ - 还是老样子 很配
- Dig deep enough，there's always shit。- We can dig if you want us to dig.
- 要是追根究底总会发现点什么 - 想要我们帮你查尽管说
What，you think he hasn't done it already？
什么 你觉得他没查过？
Thank you，Bernie.
谢谢 伯尼
- How's Kimmy？- Good。She's good.
- 金姆怎么样？ - 很好 她很好
Yeah？She sleep over yet？
是吗？她还是没回来住？
Well，let's say we're working on it.
是的 我们在努力
She appreciate the fact that you've given up your life…
为了和她亲近 你放弃了自己的生活…
…in order to be closer to her？
…对此她有谢过你吗？
What a life，huh？
什么生活 哈？
Hey，remember Beirut after the chief disappeared？
嘿 还记得头儿失踪后 我们在贝鲁特的事吗？
Bry was in deep with that crazy sheik from Hezbollah？
布莱和那个疯狂的真主党酋长耗上了？
The guy said he'd get us inside then disappeared.
那家伙扬言要把我们都弄进去 然后自己就失踪了
We're scrambling to get the hell out…
为了性命 我们可是狼狈地逃出那鬼地方…
…before we get taken down and where are you？
…那时你在哪？
I promised never to miss her birthday.
我答应过绝不会错过她的生日
Yeah，that went down well at Langley…
是啊 当他们发觉你悄然离开…
…when they found out you flew the coop…
跑去9公里外参加你女儿的生日派对…
…to attend your child's birthday 9000 miles away.
…兰格利（CIA总部）那边也没怎样
Where did you say your next posting was？
你当时说你的下个目的地是哪来着？
The Arctic Circle spying on penguins，I believe it was.
去北极观察企鹅 我想是这个
No，penguins live in Antarctica.
不 企鹅在南极
Actually，it was Alaska。What's your point，Sam？
事实上 是在阿拉斯加 你到底想说什么 萨姆？
My point is we have an open space。Say the word，it's yours.
我的意思是 只要你一句话 我们随时欢迎你回来
Who likes theirs rare？
谁要半熟的牛排？
- Guys。- See you，Bryan.
- 伙计们 - 再见 布莱恩
- Good night，guys。- See you，Bry.
- 晚安 伙计们 - 拜拜 布莱
Hey，look，look，look。All kidding aside…
嘿 听着 听着 听着 不开玩笑…
…it's a great thing trying to make up for lost time with Kimmy.
…花时间陪金姆 弥补以前的空白是件好事
But tomorrow's job？Right here.
但明天的工作呢？就在眼前
Four hours' work，2500 bucks…
工作四小时 2500元报酬…
…just for taking some pop diva to and from her concert.
…只是护送某个女歌星来回演唱会
- We're one short。- A singer？
- 还缺一个人 - 歌星？
I don't know if you'd call her a singer。More like a cash cow.
我不清楚她是否算得上歌手 她更像棵摇钱树
Twenty million records sold already and she's not even 25.
唱片销量达到两千万张 却还不到25岁
Job's a piece of cake.
工作很容易
We get her there and back。Inside，they've got their own people.
送她去那 再送回来 里面由他们自己人负责
- Okay。- Okay。Okay？
- 好的 - 好的 好的？
- Yeah。- Like that's it？
- 是啊 - 答应了？
Yeah.
对
- It'll be perfect。Just like old times。- Better。No one gets killed.
- 太好了 就像以前一样 - 比以前更好 不会有人丧命
- Tomorrow。Good night，guys。- See you.
- 明天见 晚安 伙计们 - 再见
- Get in the back，Wendy。- I always get in the back.
- 坐后面去 温迪 - 我老是坐后面
Ma'am，if you don't mind，I suggest you keep moving.
夫人 不好意思 请继续往前
My mother is ma'am，if you don't mind.
抱歉 我妈才叫夫人
- Come on，it's time now。Let's go。- Okay.
- 来 时间到了 走吧 - 好的
Bernie，Casey，you're out here。Bry，you're in the room.
伯尼 凯西 你们守在这 布莱 你进去
Okay.
好的
Let's go，let's go，let's go.
走吧 走吧 走吧
Thank you for coming.
谢谢光临
Wow，it was beautiful.
哇 好漂亮
Thanks。What did you say your name was again？
谢谢 你叫什么来着？
Mills。Bryan Mills.
米尔斯 布莱恩·米尔斯
- Nice to meet you，Bryan Mills。- You too.
- 很高兴见到你 布莱恩·米尔斯 - 很高兴见到你
- You're on。Come on，let's go now。- Okay，guys.
- 该你了 快 我们走吧 - 好的 伙计们
Excuse me，miss.
等一下 小姐
I've a daughter who wants to be a singer and was wondering if you had any tips.
我有个女儿想成为一个歌手 我想问问你有没有什么建议
Yeah，I do.
有啊
Tell her to pick another career.
告诉她别走这条路
I got one。We're waiting on an air strike…
我想到有次我们在等空袭…
…and we're waiting and then my satellite phone rings.
…我们等啊等 然后我的卫星电话响了
- Who is it？- Hello？
- 哪位？ - 喂？
- The guy we're to terminate。- Honey.
- 我们要干掉的那家伙 - 宝贝
- He'd like to know if we want some tea。- Sorry，guys，it's Kim.
- 他想知道我们是否要喝点茶 - 抱歉 各位 是金姆
The noise？
噪音？
I'm at a concert.
我在演唱会现场呢
You know this song？Yeah？
你知道这首歌？是吗？
Yep，that's her。No，no，no，I'm not attending.
对 是她 不 不 不 我不是来看演唱会的
I'm… I'm not attending.
我…我不是来看的
I'm helping some friends out with security.
我帮朋友做些保安工作
Well，of course I met her.
当然我见到她了
Who do you think's guarding her？
你以为谁在保护她啊？
I'm glad you're impressed.
听到你这么有兴趣 我很开心
Hey，I'm happy you called.
嘿 很高兴接到你的电话
I'm happy you called。What？
你能打给我 我很开心 什么？
Lunch？Tomorrow？
午餐？明天？
Sure，sure。I know the place.
当然 没问题 我知道那地方
Twelve-thirty it is.
十二点半
I'll see you then.
到时见
- Here he is。And？- What happened？
- 他来了 然后呢？ - 怎么了？
- She wants to have lunch。- Okay.
- 她要和我一起吃午饭 - 很好
- Just the two of us。- All right。Fantastic.
- 就我们俩 - 不错 太棒了
See？There's progress。That's great.
看见没？有进展 棒极了
Who left that gate open？Bry，get her out of here。Take the lead.
谁把门打开了？ 布莱 带她离开这 你领路
- Move！- Go，go！
- 走吧！ - 走 走！
More security here now！
再来些保安！
That's it。Move.
就是这样 走吧
Casey！
凯西！
Bernie，stand by，stand by.
伯尼 准备行动 准备行动
- Go，go，go。- Watch your head.
- 走 走 快走 - 小心头
Here，take this。The sugar will take the edge off the shock.
给 喝点 糖水可以压惊
Come on，come on，drink some more.
来 来 再喝点
It's okay。It's okay。You're safe.
好了 没事了 你安全了
You're safe now.
你现在很安全
Bernie.
伯尼
Casey。Rambo.
凯西 兰博
Seriously，Bry，you should think about coming with us.
认真点 布莱 你该考虑下加入我们
You've got the edge。There's more of this to be had.
你已尝到甜头了 你还可以拿到更多
- She's going to college next year？- Yep.
- 她明年要上大学了吧？ - 是的
- You're gonna lose her。- That gives me a year to find her.
- 你就要失去她了 - 一年够我找回她了
Mr。Mills，she'd like to see you.
米尔斯先生 她想要见你
- How are you feeling？- Better.
- 好点了吗？ - 好多了
So your daughter wants to be a singer？
你的女儿想当歌手？
Yep，since she was 5.
是啊 从她5岁起
It's not what everyone thinks it is.
歌手的生活并不如其他人所想的那样
Once the glam wears off，it's just a lot of hotel rooms，lots of airports.
一旦没了新鲜感 就只剩下酒店和机场的东奔西跑
It's what she wants.
她要的就是这个
The first number is Gio，my vocal coach.
第一个号码是我的声乐老师吉奥的
If he says she can sing，she can sing.
如果他说行 就代表她能唱
He'll give her coaching she needs，the fee is on me.
他会给她必要的指导 学费我来
The second number is my manager.
第二个号码是我经纪人的
If Gio clears her，he'll make sure she gets a shot.
如果吉奥肯定了她 他就能为她创造机会
- Thank you。- No，Mr。Mills，thank you.
- 谢谢 - 不 米尔斯先生 是我要谢谢你
- There she is。- Dad.
- 她来了 - 爸爸
- Hi，sweetie。- Hey.
- 嗨 宝贝 - 嗨
- Hi。- Hi.
- 你好 - 你好
Don't look so excited.
不要那么激动
I was just surprised。I thought it was just gonna be Kim and I.
我只是很惊讶 我以为就我和金姆
I asked Mom to come.
我叫妈妈来的
One raspberry-banana milkshake，extra cherries，just the way you like it.
一份覆盆子香蕉奶昔加樱桃 你最喜欢的
- Thanks。- Lennie… Lenore.
- 谢谢 - 莉妮…丽诺尔
- Would you like something？- I'm fine，thanks.
- 你要点什么？ - 不了 谢谢
So？
那么？
So，Dad，guess what.
爸爸 你猜怎么着
- You know my friend Amanda？- Yep.
- 你知道我朋友阿曼达吧？ - 嗯
Her cousins asked us to spend vacation with them in Paris.
她的表姐妹邀请我们一起去巴黎度假
How cool is that？
很酷吧？
- Why do you want to go to Paris？- Dad。Hello？
- 你怎么想去巴黎了？ - 爸爸 不会吧？
The Louvre，the lmpressionist museum，the Picasso Museum.
罗浮宫 印象派博物馆 毕加索博物馆
I didn't know you were so into art.
我不知道你会对艺术这么感兴趣
Are you kidding？I've been to the MOMA，like，a hundred times.
真的假的？ 我都去过现代艺术博物馆一百多次了
Amanda went last summer，she came back，she could practically speak French.
阿曼达去年夏天去的 回来后她都能说法语了
And because you're under 18…
因为你还未满18岁…
…you need my permission to leave the country？
…所以你要得到我的允许才能出国？
Dad，please。I really，really wanna go.
爸爸 求你了 我真的真的很想去
They've got this sick apartment overlooking the river.
她们的公寓超棒的 可以俯瞰塞纳河
- Just you and Amanda？- And her cousins.
- 就你和阿曼达？ - 还有她的表姐妹
Don't make a big deal out of this，Bryan。Just sign the paper.
别小题大作了 布莱恩 签字吧
- What？- I'm not comfortable with this.
- 什么？ - 我不放心
- Dad。- I know the world，sweetie.
- 爸爸 - 我了解这个世界 宝贝
- Dad，please。- A 17-year-old should not travel alone.
- 爸爸 求你了 - 一个17岁的姑娘不该单独出行
- I'm not gonna be alone。- Two 17-year-olds.
- 我不是一个人啊 - 两个17岁的
Amanda's 19.
阿曼达19岁了
How about this？How about if I go along？
这样如何？我和你们一起去？
You won't know I'm there。I'm very good at being invisible.
你们不会看到我的 我很擅长做隐形人
As you so amply demonstrated for most of her life.
你就不能少操点心
Just sign the paper，Bryan.
签字吧 布莱恩
I'll think about it.
我要想想
Everyone at this table knows what that means.
我们都知道那表示什么
Hey，Kimmy，there's something else.
嘿 金姆 有件好事告诉你
- I don't want anything else。- Kim.
- 我不想听 - 金姆
- I don't get you。- What？
- 真搞不懂你 - 怎么？
You sacrificed our marriage in the service of the country.
为了国家你牺牲了我们的婚姻
You made a mess of your life in service of your country.
为了国家你把自己的生活搞得一团糟
Can't you sacrifice a little this time for your daughter？
这次你就不能为你女儿牺牲一点吗？
- I would sacrifice anything for her。- What's your problem？
- 我愿意为她牺牲一切 - 那到底是什么问题？
I'm not comfortable putting my daughter at risk.
我不放心让女儿去冒险
Putting our daughter at risk by going to Paris？
去巴黎就是让女儿去冒险？
You're pathetic.
你真可悲
- She's coming。- Thanks.
- 她来了 - 谢谢
Three conditions.
三个条件
The address and phone number of where you're staying.
你住的地址和电话
You move，I wanna know where and with whom you'll be staying.
和谁出门 出门去哪里
Call me when you land。Call me every night before you go to sleep.
到了给我打电话 每晚睡前给我打电话
It's international。My number is in.
这是全球漫游的 我的号码在里面
- Okay，awesome。- Kimmy，you're not focused.
- 好吧 真啰嗦 - 金姆 你没在听
- I am。- What did I say？
- 在听呀 - 我都说了什么？
You said call you when I land，every night before I go to sleep…
你说到了给你打电话 每晚睡前给你打电话…
…your phone's international，the number's programmed in.
…你的手机是全球漫游的 你的号码就存在里面
Okay，one last thing。I get to take you to the airport.
很好 最后一件事 我送你去机场
Okay.
好吧
- There you go。- Yes.
- 拿去吧 - 耶
Thank you，Daddy。Thank you，thank you，thank you.
谢谢 爸爸 谢谢 谢谢 太谢谢了
Mom！
妈妈！
I love you，Dad.
我爱你 爸爸
Mom，he signed it，he signed it。I'm gonna go call Amanda！
妈妈 他签了 他签了 我要去给阿曼达打电话！
Wouldn't it have been easier to sign the first time？
一开始就签了不就好了？
Wouldn't it have been easier if you and I had talked about it first？
你跟我先谈下不更好？
Certain areas in Paris you should avoid。I've written them down.
在巴黎要注意的地方我都写下来了
- Dad。- Come on，take it.
- 爸爸 - 来 拿去
We're gonna be spending 90 percent of our time in museums。Don't worry.
大部分时间我们都会在博物馆 别担心
That's like telling water not to be wet，sweetie.
就像说沾水不会弄湿一样 宝贝
Mom says your job made you paranoid.
妈妈说你的工作让你神经质
Well，my job made me aware.
不 我的工作使我警觉
I used to ask Mom what your job was that you were away all the time.
我以前总是问妈妈你是做什么的 为什么你老不在家
And she would tell me to ask you.
而她让我自己问你
Whenever I did see you，I was afraid to ask.
每次看到你 我都不敢问
Yeah？Why？
是吗？为什么呢？
I don't know。Maybe because…
不知道 也许是因为…
…I was afraid to find out.
…我害怕发现
Like，maybe it was something I wouldn't like.
也许是些我不喜欢的
I worked for the government。You knew that.
我为政府工作 你知道的
So you were like a spy，right？
就像一个间谍 对吗？
- What happens if I push this button？- Don't touch that button.
- 如果我按下这个按钮会怎么样？ - 别碰
Well，no，I was a… I was a preventer，actually.
呃 不 事实上 我是… 我是负责防护工作的
- A preventer？- Yeah.
- 防护？ - 是的
What did you prevent？
防护些什么？
Bad things from happening.
防止坏事发生
So it was a good job？
那是个好工作？
Yes。Yep，it was.
对 是的
Do you miss it？
你怀念它吗？
I missed you more.
我更想念你
- Kim！- Dad，there's Amanda.
- 金姆！ - 爸爸 是阿曼达
Go ahead。I'll get the bags.
去吧 我来拿包
（欧洲地图）
（巴黎、伦敦、罗马） （柏林、马德里）
- Jimmy'll give you a hand with those。- I can manage.
- 吉米会帮你拿的 - 我自己能行
Lenore.
丽诺尔
Do you know about this？She's not just going to Paris.
你知道吗？她不仅仅去巴黎
- I know。- She lied to me.
- 我知道 - 她对我撒谎
Yes，because she can't be honest with you.
是的 因为她没法对你说实情
Why？What are you talking about？
为什么？什么意思？
Your rules and conditions.
你老说规矩啊条件啊
What is this？
这是什么？
It's U2's European tour dates.
U2的欧洲巡演日程
She's following a rock band around Europe？
她要跟随一个摇滚乐队环游欧洲？
All kids do。Stuart got her tickets，arranged her to stay in the best hotels.
孩子们都这样 斯图尔特帮她搞到了票 为她安排了最好的酒店
Best hotels。You know，you live in your little bubble here…
最好的酒店 知道吗 你住在自己的小圈子里…
…behind your wall，with your maids and chauffeurs and servants.
…有仆人和司机供差遣
No idea what the world is like.
根本不知道外面的真实世界
Yes，and neither will she unless she goes out and experiences it.
是的 可她也不知道 所以才要出去体验一下
Don't tell me I don't know the world.
不要说我不懂这个世界
For five years I waited for a phone call that didn't come for weeks at a time.
五年来我一直在等你的电话 你总是好几周都不打回来
For a knock on the door telling me there'd be no calls anymore.
我总是担心会有人敲门 告诉我你已经死了
Listen，I know you moved here to build some sort of relationship with Kimmy.
听着 我知道你搬来这 是为了重建你和金姆的关系
But you're not gonna do that by smothering her.
但你不能这样管着她
Let her live，or I promise，I promise you'll lose her.
让她去吧 否则我肯定 我肯定你会失去她
Girls.
姑娘们
Kim！
金姆！
I love you.
我爱你们
Let's go。Come on.
走吧 走
I'll teach you the French words I know.
我会教你法语
- Which may not be that much，but… - Okay。Yeah，right.
- 我会的也不多 但是… - 好的 太棒了
Three。Okay，now take one…
三 好了 照张…
Need some help？One with the two of you？
要帮忙吗？帮你们俩合影？
Yes，please.
好的 谢谢
- Okay。- He's really cute.
- 好了 - 他长得真不错
Okay。Yeah，great。Very nice.
好了 不错 很漂亮
Where are you from？
你们从哪来的？
California.
加州
真希望她们都是加州女孩
I wish they were all California girls.
No。I'm Peter.
我叫彼得
我叫阿曼达
My name is Amanda.
- This is Kim。- Hi.
- 这是金姆 - 你好
- Nice to meet you。- Hi.
- 很高兴见到你 - 你好
Hey.
嗨
You're going into Paris？
你们要去巴黎？
You know，taxis here are so damned expensive.
你们知道 这的出租车贵的要死
Want to share？
一起搭车如何？
- Yeah。Sure。- Okay，perfect.
- 好的 当然可以 - 太好了
Thanks.
谢谢
To check arrivals，please press one.
查询航班抵达 请按1
Please enter the flight number.
请输入航班
Flight 288 arrived in Paris Charles de Gaulle…
288号航班在当地时间上午8点…
…at 8 a.m。Local time.
…抵达巴黎戴高乐机场
Yeah.
耶
Oh，are you serious？
哦 不是真的吧？
- Oh，my God。- Nice address.
- 哦 我的天 - 这地方真不错
Oh，yeah，thanks.
哦 是啊 谢谢
It's my cousins'，but they're in Madrid，so we have the whole place to ourselves.
这是我表亲的 不过他们还在马德里 所以这整个地方就是我们的了
How cool is that？
很酷吧？
- I didn't know that。- It's no biggie.
- 我都不知道 - 又没什么大不了的
Well，I have to be going.
我得走了
- Nice to meet you。- Oh，okay.
- 很高兴认识你们 - 哦 好的
- You too。- Bye.
- 我们也很高兴认识你 - 再见
Hey.
嘿
There is a party tonight at school。Want to come？
今晚学校有个派对 来吗？
- Sure。Yeah。- We don't even know him.
- 当然 - 我们跟他不熟
What is there to know？He's hot.
又有什么关系？他很帅
- I come pick you up around 9？- Okay，yeah.
- 我9点来接你们？ - 好的
Okay，great。Your apartment？
好的 你们的公寓是？
- It's the whole fifth floor。Hoffmann。- Okay。See you tonight。Bye.
- 整个五楼都是 姓霍夫曼 - 好的 晚上见 拜拜
Bye.
再见
Yeah.
对
Fifth floor.
五楼
Two girls around 18.
两个18岁左右的女孩
Oh，my God.
哦 天哪
- How sick is this？- Are you kidding me？It's great.
- 完蛋了？ - 你没搞错吧？这太棒了
I just wish you would've told me they weren't gonna be here.
你应该告诉我他们不在这
- What's the difference？- I told my dad they'd be here.
- 有什么关系？ - 我跟我爸爸说他们在的
You told your dad you were going to museums too.
你还跟你爸说你会去博物馆呢
Oh，come on。He's not gonna know.
哦 得了 他不会知道的
- I'm gonna sleep with him。- Who？
- 我要和他上床 - 谁？
- Peter。- You just met him.
- 彼得 - 你才认识他
I hear French guys are amazing in bed.
听说法国人床上功夫都很好
- Maybe he has a friend，huh？- No.
- 也许他带了个朋友 哈？ - 不会吧
- No。- Oh，come on.
- 不会吧 - 哦 拜托
You gotta lose it sometime。Might as well be in Paris.
迟早会有第一次 还不如在巴黎呢
Hey！
嘿！
- Amanda，where's the bathroom？- What？
- 阿曼达 洗手间在哪？ - 什么？
I have to pee！
我要上厕所！
- Hello？- It's me。Has Kim called you？
- 喂？ - 是我 金姆给你打电话了吗？
Bryan，she's 17。She's in Paris。Give her some space.
布莱恩 她17岁了 她在巴黎 给她点空间
She'll call。Take a sleeping pill.
她会打给你的 吃片安眠药
Have a drink or something。Good night.
喝点酒什么的 晚安
Good night.
晚安
Hi，Daddy.
嗨 爸爸
Kim.
金姆
What did I say？You were supposed to call me.
我怎么说的？你该打电话给我
I'm sorry.
对不起
I thought something was wrong with the phone.
我以为手机坏了
- No。It was such a rush at the airport。- All right.
- 不 在机场太忙了 - 好吧
Well，if I'd had the number where you were staying…
要是我有你那边的号码…
…I would've just called there.
…我就直接打到那了
What's the number？
那边的电话是多少？
- I don't have it。- Kimmy，come on.
- 我还不知道 - 金姆 说吧
This is one of the conditions。Let me talk to the cousins.
这是条件之一 让我跟表亲她们讲话
I'll get it from them.
我会问她们的
Dad，they're in Spain。I didn't know。I swear.
爸爸 她们在西班牙 我不知道 我发誓
To Spain？
西班牙？
Kim，is there anything else you want to tell me？
金姆 还有什么没告诉我的？
Kimmy.
金姆
- There's someone here。- The cousins are back？
- 有人来了 - 表亲她们回来了？
No.
不是
- Oh，my God。They got Amanda。- What？
- 哦 天哪 他们抓了阿曼达 - 什么？
What are you talking about？Kimmy？
你在说什么？金姆？
- Dad。- Kim.
- 爸爸 - 金姆
- Kim。- Dad。They took her.
- 金姆 - 爸爸 他们抓了她
- They took her。- All right，listen to me.
- 他们抓住了她 - 好的 听我说
Oh，God.
哦 天哪
- Did you meet anyone on the plane？- No.
- 飞机上你们有遇到谁吗？ - 没有
- In the airport？- No。Yes，Peter.
- 机场呢？ - 没有 不 彼得
- Peter？Peter who？- I don't know.
- 彼得？他姓什么？ - 我不知道
- An American？- No.
- 美国人？ - 不是
Did he know where you were staying？
他知道你们住哪吗？
He took a cab with us.
他和我们一起搭的出租车
Dad，they're coming.
爸爸 他们要过来了
- Please，I'm scared。- I know you are.
- 救救我 我好怕 - 我知道你害怕
Stay focused，Kimmy。You have to hold it together.
集中注意力 金姆 你要冷静
How many people are there？
有多少人？
- Three，four。I don't know。- Where are you？
- 三个 四个 我不确定 - 你的位置在哪？
- I'm in the bathroom。- Go to the next bedroom.
- 我在洗手间 - 到隔壁的卧室去
Get under the bed。Tell me when you're there.
躲在床底下 躲好了告诉我
- I'm here。- Now，the next part is very important.
- 好了 - 接下来非常重要
They are going to take you。Kim，stay focused，baby。This is key.
他们会把你抓走 金姆 你要集中注意力 宝贝 这是关键
You will have five，maybe ten seconds。Very important seconds.
你会有5到10秒的时间 这几秒钟很重要
Leave the phone on the floor。Concentrate.
把电话放在地上 集中注意力
Shout out everything you see about them。Hair color，eye color，tall，short，scars.
把你看到的都说出来 发色 瞳色 身高 疤痕等等
Anything you see。You understand？
看到的一切 明白吗？
They're there。I can hear them.
他们来了 我能听见
Remember，concentrate.
记住 全神贯注
马科 你确定有两个女生吗？
Marco, are you sure there are two girls?
Put the phone closer so I can hear.
把电话放近点 我才听得到
（法语）
They're leaving。I think they're…
他们走了 我觉得他们…
爸！
Daddy!
不！
No!
Beard。Six feet。Tattoo right hand，moon and star.
有胡子 六英尺高 右手有月亮和星星的纹身
I don't know who you are.
我不知道你们是谁
I don't know what you want.
我不知道你们想要什么
If you are looking for a ransom，I can tell you，I don't have money.
如果你们要赎金 我可以告诉你们 我没钱
But what I do have are a very particular set of skills.
但是我还是有些特别的手段的
Skills I've acquired over a very long career.
都是我在漫长的职业生涯中学到的
Skills that make me a nightmare for people like you.
而这正是像你们这样的人的噩梦
If you let my daughter go now，that'll be the end of it.
如果你们放过我女儿 那么这件事到此结束
I will not look for you。I will not pursue you.
我不会去找你们 也不会追查你们
But if you don't，I will look for you.
如果你们不就此罢手 我会找到你们
I will find you…
我会找到你们…
…and I will kill you.
…然后杀了你们
Good luck.
祝你好运
Sam，it's me。I need a favor.
萨姆 是我 我需要帮助
I'm gonna download something。I need it analyzed。Right now.
我下载了些东西 帮我分析下 马上
- She's been taken。- What？
- 她被抓了 - 什么？
- Any enemies overseas？- Why would I have enemies？
- 国外的仇人？ - 为什么我会有仇人？
You do business overseas through multiple shell corporations.
你在海外利用多家空壳公司做生意
You were involved in an oil deal with a bunch of Russians that went south.
你和一伙俄罗斯人的石油生意 越来越糟糕
- How do you know that？- I was not gonna let my daughter…
- 你怎么知道的？ - 我不会让我的女儿…
…live with someone without knowing everything about them.
…和不知底细的人住一起
- I have a few resources… - Now is not the time for dick measuring.
- 我也有不少可靠消息… - 现在不是玩侦探的时候
- Anyone looking to hurt you？- Not that I know.
- 有人要伤害你？ - 就我所知没有
- Which room's Kim's？- What happened？
- 哪个房间是金姆的？ - 发生了什么事？
I got a call from her。There were people in the apartment。She was taken.
我接到她的电话 有人在公寓里 她被抓了
- Oh，God。- Which one？
- 哦 天哪 - 哪个房间？
That one.
那间
Is there something I should be doing？
我能做点什么？
You have a lease agreement with NetJet through your company.
你的公司和NetJet航空公司有租约吧
I do.
是的
- Get me a plane to Paris。- For when？
- 帮我弄架去巴黎的飞机 - 什么时候要？
An hour ago.
越快越好
- I'm gonna make the call。You all right？- Yeah，yeah。I'm okay.
- 我要打个电话 你还好吧？ - 我没事
Would you please get her back to me，Bryan？
拜托你把她带回来好吗 布莱恩？
First I have to find her.
首先我得找到她
Sam，what have you got？
萨姆 有什么发现？
They're speaking Albanian.
他们说阿尔巴尼亚语
Based on their accents and dialects，they must be from Tropoja.
从语音语调来看 他们一定来自卓帕加
The place is ground zero for scummers.
那地方是人渣们的巢穴
Even the Russians give these guys a wide berth.
就连俄罗斯人都对这些家伙敬而远之
The one you spoke to，his name is Marko.
跟你讲话的那个叫马科
We have information that a mobster boss…
我们收到消息…
…by the name of Marko Hoxha moved to Paris about six months ago.
…一个叫马科·霍查的黑道老大 六个月前搬去了巴黎
If he's the one，he's a big fish。The tattoo，by the way，is a group ID.
如果就是他 那就是条大鱼 另外那个纹身是帮派的标识
- Am I on speaker or are you by yourself？- Lenore is here.
- 我开了免提还是不止你一个人在听？ - 丽诺尔在这
- Hey，Lennie。- Hello，Sam.
- 嘿 莉妮 - 你好 萨姆
She needs to hear it，Sam.
她也想听 萨姆
The specialty of the groups coming out of this area is trafficking in women.
那块地方的帮派专门拐卖女人
- Keep going。- Okay.
- 继续 - 好的
Their previous m.o。Was to offer women from emerging East European countries…
他们之前的惯用伎俩就是向 新兴东欧国家的女人…
…like Yugoslavia，Romania，Bulgaria，jobs in the West as maids and nannies.
…像南斯拉夫 罗马尼亚 保加利亚这些国家 提供在西方做女佣和保姆的工作
Once smuggled in，they'd addict them to drugs and turn them into prostitutes.
一旦偷渡过来 就让她们染上毒瘾 逼迫她们做妓女
Lately，however，they've decided that it's more economical…
不过后来他们发现 直接绑架旅游中的年轻女人…
…just to kidnap traveling young women。Saves on transportation costs.
…更为经济 这样可以省下交通费
Oh，my little baby.
哦 我的小宝贝
What else？
还有什么？
Based on the way these groups operate，our analyst says…
根据这伙人的作案方式 我们的分析显示…
…you have a 96-hour window from the time she was grabbed.
…从她被绑开始你有96个小时的时间
- To what？- To never finding her.
- 否则呢？ - 再也找不到她
No，no，no.
不 不 不
Daddy！
爸爸！
Mustache。Six feet。Tattoo on right hand，moon and star.
有胡子 六英尺高 右手有月亮和星星的纹身
Da…
爸…
Good luck.
祝你好运
Oh，my God.
哦 我的天
Dad，they got Amanda.
爸爸 他们抓住了阿曼达
Oh，God.
哦 天哪
Dad，they got her.
爸爸 他们抓住了她
They took her.
他们抓住了她
Go to the next bedroom。Get under the bed.
到隔壁的卧室去 躲在床底下
- Tell me when you're there。- I'm here.
- 躲好了告诉我 - 好了
Stay focused，baby。Leave the phone on the floor.
精神集中 宝贝 把电话扔在地上
Concentrate。Shout out everything you see about them.
集中注意力 把你看到的都说出来
Hair color，eye color，tall，short，scars。Anything you see。You understand？
发色 瞳色 身高 疤痕等等 看到的一切 明白吗？
They're there。I can hear them。Remember，concentrate.
他们来了 我能听见 记住 全神贯注
They're leaving。Daddy！
他们走了 爸爸！
Dad！
爸爸！
Beard。Six feet。Tattoo right hand，moon and star.
有胡子 六英尺高 右手有月亮和星星的纹身
Dad！
爸爸！
各位旅客请注意
Attention, passengers.
DU720班机从斯德哥尔摩
Flight DU720 from Stockholm.
已抵达16号登机门
arrived at Gate 16.
- Hi。- Hi.
- 你好 - 你好
- I'm Peter。- I'm Ingrid.
- 我叫彼得 - 我叫英格丽德
- On holidays？- Yes.
- 度假？ - 对
- Me too。- Cool.
- 我也是 - 哇哦
Cabs here are so damned expensive。Want to share？
这的出租车贵死了 一起搭吧？
- Sure。Why not？- Great.
- 好的 为什么不呢？ - 太好了
- Excuse me。- Hey.
- 不好意思 - 嗨
- Hey。- Drive.
- 嗨 - 开车
- The two American girls from yesterday？- I don't know.
- 昨天的那两个美国女孩呢？ - 我不知道
The next rib drives into your lungs。The two American girls，where are they？
下一根肋骨可会插入你的肺 那两个美国女孩 她们在哪？
- Just like the old days。- Would you have it any other way？
- 就像以前一样 - 还有其它办法吗？
Between you and me？No.
你我之间？没了
But now that I sit behind a desk，the world looks different.
不过我做文职后 一切看起来不一样了
- You mean，looks boring。- I mean different.
- 你是指很无聊吧 - 我是说不同
Okay，a little boring。But is being retired any more interesting？
好吧 有点无聊 不过退休了能有趣吗？
It wasn't。Until my daughter disappeared in Paris yesterday.
不能 直到我女儿昨天在巴黎失踪了
She and her friend were marked by a spotter at the airport。Albanians took her.
她和她朋友在机场就被盯上了 阿尔巴尼亚人干的
- How do you know this？- I'm retired，not dead.
- 你怎么知道的？ - 我退休了 又不是死了
And I assume you don't want to go to the police.
我猜你不会去报警
I was told I have 96 hours。That was 16 hours ago.
有人告诉我 我有96个小时的时间 而那发生在16个小时前
- Okay，first，we should find the spotter。- I found him，he's dead.
- 好吧 首先我们得找到那个盯梢的 - 我找到了 但他死了
You found him that way？
你找到的时候就已经死了？
Bryan，you cannot just run around tearing down Paris…
布莱恩 你不能这样跑来跑去 把巴黎弄得天翻地覆…
I'll tear down the Eiffel Tower if I have to.
如果有必要 我连埃菲尔铁塔都能掀翻
- Don't forget who you talk to。- I'm talking to a friend.
- 不要忘了你在和谁说话 - 一个朋友
You are。But please remember，your friend has a desk now.
没错 但记住 你朋友现在是做文职的
「Deputy director，Internal Security.」 Very impressive.
「国安局副局长」 了不起
The Albanians？
阿尔巴尼亚人？
They showed up from the East，six，seven years ago.
六 七年前他们从东面过来
Fifteen，20 of them。Now there are hundreds.
有15 20个的样子 而现在有几百个了
We don't even know how many。And dangerous.
我们甚至都不知道他们究竟有多少人 也不知道他们的危险程度
So I heard。Where do I find them？
明白了 哪里可以找到他们？
The best place to start is Porte de Clichy。Bryan，try not to make a mess.
最好先从克利希酒店开始 布莱恩 不要胡来
帮我跟监一个人
Help me track someone.
小红帽跟大野狼说
Little Red Riding Hood told the Big Wolf.
「外婆 你的手臂好结实哦」
"Grandma, your arms are so sturdy.
大野狼回答…
The big wild wolf answered.
吉恩·克劳德 你助理打电话来
Gene Claude, your assistant called.
拿去
Take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂？
Hello?
他去职业介绍所雇了一个人 租了一辆车
He went to an employment agency and hired someone to rent a car.
就这样？
Is that all?
对 没什么风吹草动
Yeah, there wasn't much commotion.
持续不了太久 别被他唬了
It won't last too long Don't be fooled by him.
（克利希）
- Gregor Milocivic？- Yes。Yes，I am Gregor.
- 格莱格·米洛斯维克？ - 是的 是的 我是格莱格
I'm Mr。Smith。Get in.
我是史密斯 上车
Here is my resume.
这是我的简历
The employment agency said we would be doing translations.
职业介绍所让我来做翻译
Yes。Albanian to English。You do speak Albanian？
是的 阿尔巴尼亚语翻成英语 你真的会说阿尔巴尼亚语？
Albanian，Serbian，Croatian。I was a teacher in primary school…
阿尔巴尼亚语 塞尔维亚语 克罗地亚语 普里什蒂纳发生战争前…
- …before the war began in Pristina… - What's your rate？
- …我是个小学老师… - 你的时薪多少？
My rate？
我的时薪？
It is 25 per hour for the first three hours and then it goes up…
前三个小时25元每小时 之后涨到…
Okay。Now，here's for 10 hours。Wait here.
好的 给 这是10个小时的 等在这
Mr。Smith，I do not understand。What is the job exactly？
史密斯先生 我不明白 我到底要做什么？
Right now the job is to wait here.
现在就是在这等着
Good evening.
晚上好
- Hi。Looking for a date？- I love your dress。Is that silk？
- 嘿 找伴吗？ - 我喜欢你的衣服 丝质的？
I don't know。You want to know the prices？
不知道 想知道价钱吗？
Just the way it falls，it must be silk.
这么笔挺 一定是丝质
How it compliments the natural curves of your body.
完全凸显了你的自然曲线
The rate is 40 euros for the standard.
标准服务40欧元
Standard？Could you be more specific？
标准服务？能更具体点吗？
Back home，the standard covers a range of possibilities.
回到家 标准的内容就更广了
Like kissing，you know，closed lips，open lips.
比如亲吻 你知道的 张嘴闭嘴
- Lf you're not buying，piss off。- I didn't say I wasn't buying.
- 不要就滚蛋 - 我没说不要
I like to get comfortable before I purchase.
付钱之前我喜欢问清楚
Like this karaoke machine I bought.
就像我买的那个卡拉OK机
I must have read that manual from cover to cover so many times.
我一定会把说明书从头到尾看上好几遍
I don't give a shit。You're gonna get me in trouble if you don't buy.
这我管不着 如果你不付钱 我就麻烦了
- Trouble？Really？With who？- Piss off.
- 麻烦？真的？谁要找你麻烦？ - 滚
Okay，okay。Listen，I'm sorry.
好吧 好吧 听着 我很抱歉
If I want a package deal，do I get a discount？
如果我要整套服务 有没有折扣？
- You cost me two now。- My name's Bryan.
- 你已经让我错过了两个客人 - 我叫布莱恩
- Oh，God。You better leave。- I thought we were negotiating.
- 哦 天哪 你快点走 - 我们不是在谈价嘛
Anton，I swear，it's not my fault.
安东 我发誓 不是我的错
- I told him… - Why are you bothering the girl？
- 我跟他说… - 你为什么纠缠这个女孩？
- None of your business。- She is my business.
- 不关你的事 - 她归我管
And if you're not spending money，you're costing money.
要是你不花钱 就是在浪费我们的钱
- I was negotiating。- No negotiating。Price is the price.
- 我在谈价呢 - 没有还价 是多少就多少
Now you owe me for two that got away.
你还欠我那两个走掉的
I don't owe you nothing.
我不欠你
- Fifty euros or I kick your ass。- Sure，sure，okay.
- 50欧元 否则我揍你 - 好吧 好吧 好吧
Chill.
冷静点
Okay。Here's your 50.
给你 50元
And another 50 for being an asshole。Now get the hell out of here.
这另外50元是因为你是个浑球 滚蛋吧
If I see you again，I'll kill you.
再让我看到你 我会杀了你
Mr。Smith，I do not know what kind of job I'm supposed to do for you，but…
史密斯先生 我不清楚你要我 为你做什么样的工作 但…
- You are to translate。- Yes。But translate what？
- 你的工作是翻译 - 我知道 但翻译什么呢？
This.
这个
Translate.
翻译
- They're talking about you。- What about me？
- 他们在说你 - 说我什么？
- They're not saying nice things。- Be specific.
- 不太好听 - 具体点
- They're saying… Excuse me，Mr。Smith。- What an asshole you are.
- 他们在说…不好意思 史密斯先生 - 你是个浑球
Please，if you can explain to me why we're doing this…
拜托 你能不能告诉我为什么要做这个…
Just translate.
翻译
One of them says，the sausage gave him heartburn.
一个人说 香肠吃得他胃痛
Keep going.
继续
The other one is suggesting something his grandmother used to give him.
另一个在说他的祖母以前给过他什么
- Do you really want to hear all this？- Every word.
- 你真的要听这个吗？ - 每句话
Now they're talking about football。The game between Lazio and Marseille.
现在他们在谈论足球 拉齐奥和马赛的比赛
And they lost money on the betting.
他们赌输了
- Perhaps if I knew the purpose… - You're better off not knowing.
- 如果我知道目的… - 你最好不要知道
Is it still football？
还在说足球？
One is on the phone.
一个人在打电话
He has to do a job at the construction site.
他得去工地办点事
Something about fresh merchandise giving problems.
新来的货物出了点问题
Mr。Smith，I do not understand any of this.
史密斯先生 我一点都不明白
You're not supposed to。Goodbye.
不明白最好 再见
I asked for an English-Albanian dictionary，did you bring one？
我要的英阿字典 你带来了吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
I love you.
我爱你
Where did you get this？
从哪弄来的？
你从哪弄来的？
- I'm good。- Who gave this to you？
- 我很好 - 谁给你的？
- Who… Who gave this to you？- I'm good.
- 谁…谁给你的？ - 我很好
Hey.
嗨
Come on.
坚持住
我早说过他不可能按兵不动太久
I told you earlier that he couldn't have stood still for too long.
现在怎么办？
What should we do now?
他现在行动了 我猜他会甩掉你
He's taking action now. I guess he'll get rid of you.
干！
Damn it!
Monsieur Allen，how are you？
艾伦先生 你好吗？
Hello，Gilles。How's the wife？
你好 吉勒斯 你妻子怎么样？
Well，still in charge.
还在看护着
- Been a long time since I've seen you。- Way too long.
- 好久不见了 - 很久了
- The usual accommodation？- Plus one.
- 老房间？ - 加一间
Yes？
喂？
- We need to talk。- I'm listening.
- 我们得谈谈 - 我听着
Well，can't you come and meet me first？
你不先过来看看我吗？
I can't see you。Where are you？
我没看到你 你在哪？
I can see you and hear you very well.
我能很清楚地看到你 听到你
You can tell them to stop jogging now.
叫他们别跑了
好 收到讯号了
Okay, I got the signal.
正在搜寻
Searching.
正在查讯号发送地点
Checking for signal sending location.
Didn't think I was gonna come down，did you？
没想到我会来 对吧？
I didn't think you were gonna make such a mess.
我没想到你会搞得这样一团糟
I didn't have time to worry about neatness.
我没空考虑乱不乱了
- I know。You have 70 hours。- Now I have 56.
- 我知道 你还有70个小时 - 现在只有56个小时了
找到他了
I find him.
No，now you have none.
不 现在你一个小时也没了
My chief wanted to arrest you，I convinced him to send you home.
我的上司要逮捕你 我说服他把你遣送回去
Air France 001 leaves today at 2。First class.
法国航空001航班 今天2点起飞 头等舱
Courtesy of the French government for past services rendered.
法国政府对于你过去所做贡献的特别招待
- And what about my daughter？- I told you，I sit behind a desk now.
- 我女儿怎么办？ - 跟你说了 我现在是做文职的
I take my orders from someone who sits behind a bigger desk.
我得听从上司的命令
Come on，seven dead bodies，three in hospital，a building destroyed.
听听 七具尸体 三个住院 一幢大楼被毁
Total chaos at the airport.
还有机场的骚乱
He wanted your ass in chains。It's the best I could do，I'm sorry.
他要你坐牢 我已经尽力了 很抱歉
Sorry doesn't cut it，Jean-Claude。Not this time.
说抱歉没用 吉恩·克劳德 这次不行
You can't beat the state，Bryan。You know that.
你斗不过政府的 布莱恩 你明白的
I'm not trying to。I'm trying to save my daughter.
我才不想斗 我只是想救回我的女儿
It was a trailer，not a building.
那是一辆拖车 不是大楼
有没有找到他？
Did you find him?
没有
No.
（阿尔巴尼亚实用字典）
No，no，no。Leave it.
不 不 不 别动它
It's all right，it's fluids.
没事 这是点滴
And medication to counteract the drugs.
里面是中和毒品的药物
It's all right.
没事的
Where'd you get this？
从哪弄来的？
Where did you get this jacket？
你从哪弄来这件外套？
Did you get it from her？
从她那弄来的？
Was it from this girl？
是这个女孩的吗？
I didn't steal it.
我没偷
- I was cold，she gave it to me。- Where？Where did she give it to you？
- 我很冷 是她给我的 - 在哪里？她在哪里给你的？
- In the house。- What house？
- 房子里 - 哪座房子？
The house with the red door.
有扇红门的房子
Sorry.
对不起
He said it was a party.
他说那是个派对
The girl who gave you this，was she in the house？
给你外套的那个女孩在房子里吗？
She was nice.
她是好人
I know.
我知道
She's my daughter.
她是我女儿
I need to find this house。Do you know where it is？
我必须找到那座房子 你知道在哪吗？
Paradise.
天堂
- Good morning。- May I help you？
- 早上好 - 有事吗？
- I'm here to see your boss。- No boss.
- 我要见你们老板 - 老板不在
We're doing nothing wrong here.
我们没做什么非法的事
One button，and 30 agents will be here…
按一下 30个特工就会出现在这…
…before you have time to scratch your balls.
…你们根本没时间卷铺盖走人
Stop jerking around before I close you down for wasting my time.
别耍人了 再浪费我时间 小心我干掉你
Wait here.
在这等着
You have weapon？
你带着武器？
You're holding it.
你手上拿着呢
Black，one sugar，please.
黑咖啡 一块糖 谢谢
What is it you want？
你要什么？
I'm here to negotiate the rates.
我是来谈价钱的
We already negotiated the rate with Mr。Macon.
我们和梅肯先生谈过了
Mr。Macon has moved to another division.
梅肯先生调到别的区了
I'm here for the renegotiation.
我是来重新谈的
Unless you think I'm being unreasonable，let me explain ourselves.
觉得我有道理的话 那我接着说了
Nice coffee。We have you under satellite surveillance，24 hours a day.
咖啡不错 我们利用卫星全天24小时监视你们
We hear everything you say，we know everything you do.
你们说的每句话 做的每件事 我们都知道
Do you have any idea what it costs just to change the angle…
你知不知道 光是改变地球上空200米…
…of the lens on a satellite orbiting 200 miles above the Earth？
…轨道卫星的镜头角度 就要花多少钱？
And those costs have gone up.
而且价格还在上涨
Our costs go up，your costs go up。It's only logical.
我们的费用上涨 随之你们的费用也得上涨 再正常不过了
By the way，which one of you is Marko？
另外 你们谁是马科？
Why do you want to know？
你问这干嘛？
I was told Marko is in charge.
我听说马科是这的老大
We are all Marko.
我们都是马科
Marko from Tropoja.
马科来自卓帕加
We are all from Tropoja.
我们都来自卓帕加
If that's the game you want to play，the rate just went up 10 percent.
如果你们那么想玩游戏 那么费用上升10%
If you are trying to extort us because we are immigrants，we know the law.
不要以为我们是移民就可以敲诈我们 我们懂法律
I'm extorting you because you are breaking the law.
我敲诈你们是因为你们做了违法的事
Which charge would you like to be arrested for？
你们喜欢以哪项罪名被捕？
Drugs，kidnapping，prostitution？Take your pick.
贩毒 绑架 卖淫？随你们挑
You come to this country，take advantage of it…
你们来到这个国家 利用这个国家…
…and think because we are tolerant，we are weak and helpless.
…我们宽容并不代表我们懦弱无助
Your arrogance offends me.
你们的傲慢无礼激怒了我
For that，the rate went up 10 percent.
为此 费用提升10%
Now，do you want to get down to business or to keep playing？
现在 你们要谈正事还是继续玩？
- How much？- Twenty percent.
- 多少？ - 20%
And you have my word it'll not go up for a year.
而且我保证一年内不会上涨
把罐子给我
Give me the jar.
How do you say 「sugar」 in your language？
用你们的语言如何说「糖」？
You've made a very good investment，gentlemen.
你们做了明智的决定 先生们
See you in a month.
一个月后见
A friend gave this to me。It's Albanian。You mind translating it？
一个朋友给我的 是阿尔巴尼亚语 不介意翻一下吧？
Good luck.
祝你好运
- Good luck。- Good luck.
- 祝你好运 - 祝你好运
- Good luck。Good luck。- Good luck.
- 祝你好运 祝你好运 - 祝你好运
You don't remember me.
你不记得我了
We spoke on the phone two days ago.
两天前我们通过电话
I told you I would find you.
我告诉过你我会找到你
Kim.
金姆
Amanda.
阿曼达
Wake up！
醒醒！
I need you to be focused.
我要你集中精神
Are you focused yet？
精神集中了吗？
Where is this girl？
这女孩在哪？
Where is she？
她在哪？
You know，we used to outsource this kind of thing.
你知道 我们以前会外包这种事
But what we found was the countries we outsourced to…
但我们发现 我们外包的那些国家…
…had unreliable power grids。Very Third World.
…电网都不怎么稳定 典型的第三世界
You'd turn on a switch，power wouldn't come on…
你按了开关 却没有电…
…and then tempers would get short。People would resort to pulling fingernails.
…真是气死人 没办法 就只能拔指甲
Acid drips on bare skin.
在裸露的皮肤上洒酸溶液
The whole exercise would become counterproductive.
这些只会造成反效果
But here，the power's stable.
但在这里 电力很稳定
Here，there's a nice even flow.
这里的电流源源不断
Here，you can flip a switch and the power stays on all day.
轻按开关 电力就能持续一整天
Where is she？
她在哪？
Now，I don't have any more time to waste，Marko from Tropoja.
我可没什么时间可以浪费 卓帕加的马科
Give me what I need or this switch'll stay on…
回答我 否则这个开关会一直开着…
…till they turn power off for lack of payment on the bill.
…直到他们付不出电费而关掉
Where is my daughter？
我女儿在哪？
We don't keep virgins，we sell them.
我们不会留着处女 我们会卖了她们
She was virgin，lot of money.
她是处女 可以卖一大笔
You sold my daughter？You sold her？
你把我女儿卖了？你把她卖了？
To who？
卖给谁了？
I don't know.
我不知道
- What？- Saint-Clair.
- 什么？ - 圣·嘉力
Saint-Clair.
圣·嘉力
Saint-Clair？Saint-Clair。Is that a person，a place？
圣·嘉力？圣·嘉力 是个人 还是个地方？
Person。Patrice Saint-Clair.
是个人 帕特里斯·圣·嘉力
Patrice Saint-Clair.
帕特里斯·圣·嘉力
Where can I find him？
在哪能找到他？
I don't know，I don't know.
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know。I don't know。I don't know.
我不知道 我不知道 我不知道
Please！I don't know！
求求你！我真的不知道！
I don't know！No！Please！Please.
我不知道！不！求求你！求求你
Please.
求求你
Not that。Please.
不要 求求你
I believe you.
我相信你
But it's not gonna save you.
但我不能放过你
我回来了
I'm back.
爸爸！
Daddy!
嗨 宝贝们
Hi, babies.
爸爸
Daddy.
烤鸡好香哦
Roasted chicken is so delicious.
Look who dropped by.
看看谁来了
Bryan，what a pleasant surprise.
布莱恩 真是意外啊
Jean-Claude.
吉恩·克劳德
The children waited up for you.
孩子们在等你
If you tuck them in，maybe we can eat before everything gets cold.
快带他们去睡觉 我们还能吃顿热乎乎的
Bryan，will you do the honors？
布莱恩 来帮下忙？
- Sure。- I'll be just a minute.
- 好的 - 我马上来
I was just telling Bryan how nice it's been…
我正跟布莱恩说 你换了新工作后…
…since you left the old job for the new one.
…一切变得好多了
Home every night for dinner，get to see the kids more.
每晚回家吃饭 见到孩子们的时间也多了
Yeah，must be nice coming home every night，seeing your kids.
每晚回家 看着孩子们 一定很幸福
Bryan has been thinking about relocating.
布莱恩在考虑搬家
- Really？- Yes.
- 真的？ - 是的
To Paris，he's been visiting houses.
搬到巴黎 他在看房子了
- White or dark meat？- Dark，please.
- 要鸡胸还鸡腿？ - 鸡腿 谢谢
Find anything interesting？
有看上的吗？
As a matter of fact，I did，in the 10th arrondissement on Rue Paradis.
说实话 有啊 在天堂街第十区
People there know someone that works in your office.
住那的人认识你的一个同事
A Mr。Macon。Do you know him？
一位梅肯先生 你认识吗？
Oh，Henry。I call him Mr。Nervous.
哦 亨利 我都叫他紧张先生
Always seems like he's about to have a problem。Carrots？
总是一副会有麻烦的样子 要胡萝卜吗？
I got to the bottom of it，Jean-Claude.
我查到了 吉恩·克劳德
I know everything.
我什么都知道了
I hope you're not involved in this shit.
我希望你没趟进这浑水
- What shit？- This is not the time or place，Bryan.
- 什么浑水？ - 现在不该说这些 布莱恩
- Are you involved？- Involved in what？
- 你掺合进来了？ - 掺合进什么？
What are you two talking about？
你们俩在说什么？
- Are you？- My salary is X，my expenses are Y.
- 是不是？ - 我的薪水是X 我的开支是Y
As long as my family is provided for…
只要能养家…
…I do not care where the difference comes from.
…我不在乎从哪弄钱
That is my entire involvement.
我就是那样卷进来的
- What about my family？- I told you…
- 那我的家人呢？ - 我告诉你…
…I would help as long as it didn't cause trouble.
…只要不惹麻烦 我会帮你的
Who is Patrice Saint-Clair？
谁是帕特里斯·圣·嘉力？
I don't know，I don't care。I am driving you to the airport.
我不知道 我也不关心 我载你去机场
Jean-Claude.
吉恩·克劳德
闭嘴 伊莎贝尔！
Shut up, Isabel.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
Let's get going。Dinner is over.
走吧 晚餐结束了
- I'm not finished yet。- Yes，you are.
- 我还没吃完 - 不 你吃完了
- No！- No，I'm not.
- 不！ - 不 我还没有
That's what happens when you sit behind a desk。You forget things.
那就是你做文职的后果 你忘了些事
Like the weight in the hand of a gun that's loaded.
就如你都忘了 上了弹的枪拿在手上的重量
Isabelle！
伊莎贝尔！
你这个王八蛋！
You bastard.
It's a flesh wound.
只是皮肉伤
But if you don't get me what I need，the last thing you'll see…
但你再不说 就会看到你最不想看的…
…is the bullet I put between her eyes.
…我会射穿她的脑门
Now，Patrice Saint-Clair.
现在 告诉我谁是帕特里斯·圣·嘉力
You could've made this less painful…
你本可以少受点苦…
…if you had been more concerned about my daughter and less about your desk.
…只要你多关心点我女儿 而不是你的职位
Please apologize to your wife for me.
请替我向你妻子道歉
- Can I help you？- Yes，I'm here to see Mr。Saint-Clair.
- 能为您效劳吗？ - 我来找圣·嘉力先生
Your name，please.
请告诉我您的名字
I'm sorry，your name is not on the list.
抱歉 上面没有您的名字
Oh，please check again.
哦 请再检查一次
Inside.
进去
May I help you，sir？
需要帮忙吗 先生？
- Your champagne。- Yeah，I will take it.
- 您点的香槟 - 没错 放这吧
I have 50，000。Fifty thousand.
现在出价5万 5万
Fifty thousand.
5万
One hundred，100，000.
10万 10万
One hundred，150.
10万 15万
I have 150.
现在出价15万
Your champagne，sir.
您的香槟 先生
Two，I have two，250.
20万 现在出价20万 25万
May I serve？
要为您倒酒吗？
- Please。- I have 250.
- 谢谢 - 现在出价25万
Two-fifty.
25万
Sold for 250，000.
25万成交
阁下 出价如你所愿
Your bid is as you wish.
还有一个物件要拍卖
There is another item to be auctioned off.
我们马上就回来
We'll be right back.
The last item.
最后一件拍品
As usual，we save the best for last.
惯例 最好的留到最后
Speaks English，some French.
说英语 会一点法语
Certified pure.
绝对是处女
- Sorry。- Get out.
- 对不起 - 出去
The bidding will begin at 100，000.
起价为10万
One hundred.
10万
One hundred thousand.
- I said… - I heard what you said.
- 我说… - 我听到了
Buy her.
买下她
I have 100.
现在出价10万
- Buy her。- One-fifty.
- 买下她 - 15万
Two hundred.
20万
Two-fifty，three，350.
25万 30万 35万
Three hundred and fifty thousand.
35万
Four。Four.
40万 40万
Four-fifty，450.
45万 45万
Four hundred and fifty thousand.
45万
Four-fifty.
Five hundred。Five hundred thousand.
50万 50万
Five hundred thousand。Sold.
50万 成交
That concludes the sales for tonight。Thank you all for coming.
今晚的拍卖到此结束 谢谢各位的惠顾
- You can collect your purchases directly。- Move.
- 你可以直接领走你的商品 - 走
- You will never get away with this。- Lf you wanna live，you'll make sure I do.
- 你逃不掉的 - 要是你想活着 你就得保证我也活着
Now，Mr？
先生？
Well，we know you're not this man。So，what do we call you？
我们知道你不是这个人 但我们该怎么叫你？
It doesn't matter what we call you…
我们怎么叫你不重要…
…what does matter is what you're doing here.
…重要的是你来这干嘛
The last girl，I'm her father.
最后那女孩 我是她父亲
- Oh，my。- Give her to me.
- 哦 我的天 - 把她还给我
I wish I could，honestly.
说实话 我希望我能
See，I'm a father myself.
看 我也是个父亲
I have two sons and a daughter…
我有两个儿子 一个女儿…
…but let me tell you something，Mr。Whoever-You-Are.
…但是我必须告诉你 不管你叫什么
This is a business.
这是生意
This is a very unique business…
这是和特殊客户…
- …with a very unique clientele。- I'll pay.
- …做的特殊生意 - 我会付钱
In this business，you have no refunds，returns…
这种生意 你不能退款 退货…
…discounts，buybacks。All sales are final.
…没有折扣 回购 一经售出便成定局
Besides discretion，it's about the only rule we have.
除了决定权 这是我们唯一的一条规则
Kill him。Quietly。I have guests.
杀了他 安静点 我还有客人
Would you please go see which part of 「quietly」…
你去看看 我让他们「安静点」…
- …they did not understand？- Yes，sir.
- …他们听不懂吗？ - 是 先生
Okay，we can resolve this。I know how you feel.
好吧 我们可以解决的 我明白你的感受
We should talk，okay？We can work this out.
我们谈谈 怎么样？我们会找到办法的
You have no idea…
你不知道…
- Where is she？- Please.
- 她在哪？ - 别
Understand。Please try…
请理解 请试着…
There's a boat by the quay.
码头那有条船
Please understand.
请你明白
It was all business，it wasn't personal.
这都是生意 我们无冤无仇的
It was all personal to me.
现在有仇了
她们都准备好了
They're all ready.
你带这几个女孩去见老板
You take these girls to see the boss.
你跟我来
Come with me.
有人入侵 搜船
Someone invaded and searched the ship.
有必要就杀了他
Kill him if necessary.
3号 出了什么事？
No.3, What happened on the third?
你在哪里 3号？
Where are you? No.3.
待在房里比较安全 阁下
It's safer to stay in the room, sir.
出了什么事？是谁？
What happened? Who is it?
那个女孩的爸爸 他要带她回去
That girl's father. He's taking her back.
我来处理那条狗
I'll handle that dog.
We can…
我们能…
- Daddy。- Kim.
- 爸爸 - 金姆
You came for me.
你来救我了
I told you I would.
我说过我会的
May I have your attention。If you're waiting for oversized bags…
乘客们请注意 如果各位在等你们的大号行李箱…
Mom.
妈妈
Oh，my God.
哦 天哪
Oh，sweetie.
哦 宝贝
Oh，here，let me get that for you.
哦 来 我帮你拿
Bryan，if there's anything you need…
布莱恩 如果你需要什么…
I've got everything I need.
我已经拥有了我想要的一切
I love you so much.
我很爱你
Stuart.
斯图尔特
Thank you.
谢谢
Attention，travelers。You are not required to…
请注意 游客们 你们不用…
Shall we go？
走了吗？
Sure you don't wanna ride with us？
你确定不用载你一程？
- I'll be fine。I'll take a cab。Thanks。- All right.
- 没关系 我可以叫车 谢谢 - 好的
- I love you，Dad。- Love you too.
- 我爱你 爸爸 - 我也爱你
- Where are we？- I told you。It's a surprise.
- 这是哪？ - 跟你说了 这是一个惊喜
- Hi。- Hi.
- 你好 - 你好
When someone says 「hi，」 it's usually polite to say 「hi」 back.
有人跟你说「你好」时 通常应礼貌地回应「你好」
Hi.
你好
I heard you wanna be a singer.
我听说你想当歌手
- I do。- She does.
- 是的 - 没错
Well，come on in。Let's see what you got.
进来吧 让我们听听你唱得如何